

Oleksandr Haruca

Front-end developer

Ready to work remotely

Graduated from the Kyiv National Economic University and received a diploma in enterprise strategy and consulting. Had taken part in the student exchange program and studied in the UK.

Kyiv, Ukraine
Phone: +38 093 000 26 00
E-mail: al.haruca@gmail.com
Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/alex-haruca
Telegram: @a_haruca
Github: github.com/uliton

I have a lot of experience in different industries. Auto services, sales, operational management, agricultural sector, private enterprise. All this experience has helped me achieve many cool projects with good results. I'm sure it will help me find a common language within a team and find solutions in difficult situations. I also know how to look at the business as a whole, so that it gives me the opportunity to offer complex solutions.

I have over 2000 hours of coding and my main stack consists of React, JavaScript, HTML and CSS. And I'm also open to learning Vue, React Native, Angular and any other technology.

SKILLS

Working with: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, TypeScript, Git, NPM, ESLint, Sass(SCSS), Redux, REST API,

SQL, classNames, localeStorage, Routing, SVG, JSON

Frameworks: Material Ui, Bootstrap, Bulma

Tools: AWS, Figma Methodologies: BEM

English level: Intermediate Basic understanding of OOP

EDUCATION

Graduated from Kyiv National Economic University (KNEU) in 2004, specializing in economics and entrepreneurship with advanced English studying, got a bachelor's degree.

Received a master's degree in consulting in 2005.

Passed 3-months English summer school in Great Britain in 2002.

SELF EDUCATION

- mate academy
- developer.mozilla.org
- stackoverflow.com
- w3schools.com
- reactjs.org

PORTFOLIO

Union Stone => <u>uliton.github.io/union</u>

Technologies used: JS, React, JSON, SVG, SASS, Hooks, classNames, Routing, Flex, Grid

USA Map => uliton.github.io/usa_map

Technologies used: JS, TS, React, JSON, SVG, SASS

Ideas calendar => <u>uliton.github.io/ideas_calendar</u>

Technologies used: JS, React, Hooks, SASS, localeStorage

Personal website where I collect video evidence of Russian occupiers => okupant.online

Technologies used: JS, React, Hooks, SASS, classNames, Routing

Freelance project => <u>uliton.github.io/GR_shipping</u>

Technologies used: JS, React, Hooks, SASS, classNames

Countries => <u>uliton.github.io/countries</u>

Technologies used: JS, TS, React, Redux, Hooks, REST Api, SASS, classNames

Dictionary => uliton.github.io/dictionary

Technologies used: React, Redux, Hooks, localeStorage

Users posts => <u>uliton.github.io/users_posts</u>

Technologies used: JS, TS, React, REST API

Personal App with a list of companies that are hiring junior IT specialists => uliton.github.io/job_for_jun

Technologies used: JS, TS, React, REST API, localeStorage

Currency Converter => uliton.github.io/currency_converter

Technologies used: JS, React, debounce, REST API

Users form=> uliton.github.io/users_form

Technologies used: React, Hooks, Grid, Material UI, REST Api

Recursive list=> uliton.github.io/recursive_list

Technologies used: localStorage

Landing BAKERY => uliton.github.io/bakery-landing

Technologies used: HTML, BEM, CSS, Grid

Landing MIAMI => uliton.github.io/miami-landing

Technologies used: HTML, BEM, CSS, Flex

SPORT

- Candidate Master of Sports in short distance swimming
- Professionally engaged in auto-sports from 2003 to 2012. Karting, drag racing, drifting.

EXPERIENCE

Front-end developer (2022 - present)

Since the summer of 2022 I have been working as a freelancer. Completed simple, single tasks. And also made some interesting projects using different technologies.

Front-end studding (2021 - 2022)

Graduate from Mate Academy Front-end course in summer of 2022. It takes near 6 month of full time learning. Made more than 50 pet projects.

Marketing & Project manager at Agro business with "SUPERHERO" (2016 - 2021)

List of significant results and impact:

- experienced in exporting products to the European Union
- experienced in certification of organic products in the European Union and according to Canadian quality standards

List of responsibilities:

- development of agro-technology and technological map for the season for each of the crops grown
- development of promotional materials, packaging, branding, logistics

Technologies: the use of not only traditional agro-technologies, but also new technologies, such as hydroponic, aeroponic, flooding technology, low-volume technology...

Project manager at Retail businesses (2012 - 2016)

List of significant results and impact:

retail network increased

List of responsibilities:

- work with suppliers
- accounting

Project & Event manager at Auto business with LINEYKA (2010 - 2012), RED LINE (2009 - 2010)

List of significant results and impact:

- building racing cars for champions in different disciplines
- development of motorsport culture in Ukraine
- organization of championships in different disciplines (karting, drag-racing, drifting)
- organization of international events with the participation of foreign pilots

List of responsibilities:

- search for the necessary parts for the construction of racing cars
- organization of sports events (planning, PR, implementation, report)
- organization of security at the event (ambulance, fire, police)
- coordination with local government

Marketing manager at IT-startup ALGATA (2006 - 2007)

It was an IT startup.

List of significant results and impact:

- developing a product related to the provision of online video content services List of responsibilities:
 - to develop commercial offers for potential customers and advertisers